《疯狂》杂志
《花花公子》
十八禁
吉米  扫地扫得怎么样了
Jimmy, how's that sweepin' going?
扫着呢  老爸
Goin' good, pop.
你好吗
Hi. How are ya?
你好  先生
Hello, sir.
不知道你能不能帮我个忙
Uh, I was wondering if maybe you could help me.
什么事
Yeah?
我今早开车进城
Well, I drove into the city this morning.
通常我都搭火车  但今天特别赶时间
U-usually, I take the train, but I was in just such a rush
急着给我儿子弗莱迪买药
to get some medicine for my son, Freddie.
他有癫痫
He has epilepsy.
今天早上发作的时候
He had an attack this morning, but during his fit,
打翻了我妻子手中的药
he knocked the bottle of medicine out of my wife's hand
砰一声  撒了一地
and just -- bam, one huge puddle.
真糟糕
That's terrible.
长话短说吧  我开车进城
Well, long story short -- drove into town,
身上所有钱都拿去买了药
bought the new medicine with every last nickel in my pocket,
接着我的车就抛锚了
and then my car died.
我的天  这实在...
Oh, god, that's -- that's just, uh...
我知道
I know.
屋漏偏逢连夜雨  对吧
When it rains, it pours, right?
我试着发动  怎么也点不着
I-I tried the ignition, just nothin' -- not firing.
总之  我只知道
And, anyway, now I've convinced myself
在我带药回家之前
that Freddie's ‭gonna have another seizure
弗莱迪的癫痫随时会再次发作
before I get back with the medicine.
要是你能帮我  我会感激不尽
So, i-if you can help me, I would be so grateful.
我可以帮你检查一下车子
Well, I could come out and check your car for ya.
可能只是火花塞的问题
You know, ‭maybe it's just a spark plug.
我储藏室里有一盒火花塞
I-I-I got a box of plugs back in the stockroom.
谢谢  我很感激
Thanks, ‭and I-I appreciate that,
但如果你能给我五块就好了...
but if you could possibly just spare $5 instead...
我宁可打车也不愿再折腾我那破车
I'd rather grab a cab than take a chance with my old clunker.
好啊  五元
Yeah, $5.
如果能给的话
I-if you can spare it.
行  当然
Yeah, okay, sure.
爸  过来一下
Dad, c'mere!
过来一下
C'mere!
爸  这是诈骗  跟上周那个乞丐一样
Dad, it's a rip-off, just like that bum from last week.
吉米
Jimmy.
镇上的骗棍都知道
Every grifter in town knows that
这里是骗取施舍的好地点
this is the spot to come for an easy handout.
"骗棍"  你哪里学来的词
Grifter? Where in the world did you learn that word?
爸  他鬼话连篇
Dad, his story's baloney.
他多半根本没有儿子
He probably doesn't even have a son.
他在敲诈你
He's conning you.
吉米  万一你错了呢
Jimmy... What if you're wrong?
这样吧
Y-you know what?
很抱歉麻烦你们  我这就走
Sorry to bother you folks. I-I'm gonna get outta here.
-我这就...  -不不不
- I-I'm gonna... - No, no, no, no, no.
-爸  -不  不麻烦
- Dad. - ‭No, no bother.
来吧  这儿
Come on. Now, here.
给你十元吧
There's $10 for you.
先生  你...
Sir, y-you're --
真的很慷慨
That's -- that is so generous.
没事  这样吧
Of course, and -- and you know what?
我去后面储藏室
I'm gonna go back in the stockroom.
找点火花塞
I'm gonna find those spark plugs.
或许能帮你把车发动  如何
Maybe we'll get your car started for you, okay?
来吧  吉米  帮我看一会儿行吗
Come on, Jimmy. Just man the till, okay?
我马上回来
And I'll just be back in a jiff, okay?
一条酷尔烟多少钱
How much for a carton of Kools?
四块钱
4 bucks.
好  来一条
Yeah, gimme a carton.
先付钱
Money first.
来两条吧
Gimme two cartons.
天啊
Oh, gosh.
火花塞分明就在这里
These spark plugs are back here somewhere.
再给我一分钟好吗
Just give me one more minute, okay?
快点吧
Come on.
这世上有两类人  狼和羊  孩子
There are wolves and sheep in this world, kid.
狼和羊
Wolves and sheep --
想清楚你要成为哪一种
Figure out ‭which one you're gonna be.
等等
Wait. Just...Just...
好啦  找到了
Okay, I-I found the, um...
他走了吗
Did he leave?
他刚走吗
Oh, did he just leave?
先生
Sir!
别让我打扰你
Don't let me interrupt.
抱歉  准备好了吗
Sorry. You ready?
走吧  赶紧把这事解决了
Hey, come on. Let's get this over with.
感谢您抽空见我们
Thank you for seeing us.
我们不想耽误太久
We don't wanna take up too much of your time,
我就开门见山吧
so I'll get right to it.
很遗憾地告诉你们  经过事后回忆
Um, I regret to inform you that with the benefit of hindsight,
厄门绍特先生决定小小地修改一下陈述
Mr. Ehrmantraut will be amending his original statement a tad.
-小小地  -一点点
- A tad? ‭- A wee bit.
他决定不能再昧着良心
He's decided that he can no longer in good conscience claim
说现场发现的枪是屠库·塞拉曼加的
claim that the gun found at the scene belonged to Tuco Salamanca.
-那是谁的枪呢  -谁知道呢
- So, whose gun was it? ‭- Who's to say?
你知道阿尔布开克有多少枪吗
You know how many guns there are in Albuquerque?
少如响尾蛇  多则如沙粒
Somewhere between the number of rattlesnakes and grains of sand.
反正很多
So...a lot.
是你的枪吗  厄门绍特先生
Was it your gun, Mr. Ehrmantraut?
他没这么说
No, he's not saying that.
能让厄门绍特先生自己说吗
Can we hear it from Mr. Ehrmantraut?
枪不是塞拉曼加的
The gun wasn't Salamanca's.
我只知道这么多
That's all I can tell you.
你原来说是他的
You told us it was.
你说塞拉曼加掏出枪指着你
You said Salamanca pulled it and pointed it at you.
他没有
Well, he didn't.
-你为什么要改陈述  -好公民嘛
- Why are you changing your story? ‭- Good citizenship.
枪上只有一个人的指纹
Look, there was only one set of prints on the gun --
塞拉曼加的
Salamanca's.
枪怎么可能不是他的呢
How's that gonna happen if it wasn't his?
这个就不能问我的委托人了  对吧
That's not really for my client to say, now, is it?
他又不是鉴定专家
He's not a forensics expert.
谁知道呢  说不定
Who knows? Maybe it, uh,
是从飞过的鸟儿嘴里掉下来的
fell ‭from a passing bird's beak,
塞拉曼加先生接住了枪想扔掉
and Mr. Salamanca caught it and tried to throw it away.
可能性多了去了
I mean, ‭the possibilities are endless.
塞拉曼加威胁你了吗  厄门绍特先生
Did Salamanca threaten you, Mr. Ehrmantraut?
我们想让他多关几年
We wanna put this guy away for years.
枪是最关键的  你们知道
The gun makes all the difference. You know that.
你想让他早点出来再次伤害你吗
You gonna let this person victimize you twice?
别说枪的事了  行吗
Forget about the gun, all right?
枪不是塞拉曼加的
The gun was not Salamanca's.
如果你们要把枪纳为证据
If you try to introduce it into evidence,
厄门绍特先生会帮被告人辩护
Mr. Ehrmantraut ‭will make himself available to the defense,
他会澄清是非
and he will set the record straight,
直截了当  毫不含糊
categorically and unequivocally.
他威胁你了  还是贿赂你了
Did he threaten you or pay you off?
够了  到此为止  走吧
Okay, that's it. We're done. Okay. Let's go.
你没做错
You're doing the right the thing.
这个叫塞拉曼加的
This Salamanca character?
简直是疯子
Maniac.
我自己也
I had my own...
跟他打过交道
...thing with him.
之前因为利益冲突啊啥的  就没有说
I didn't wanna say it before because of conflict of interest,
但是他确实是个神经病
yadda yadda, but, yeah, he's nuts.
他把我五花大绑带到沙漠里
I'm talking he had me hog-tied in the desert
拿枪顶着我脑袋
with a gun to my head.
当着我的面折了两个家伙的腿
Broke two guys' legs right in front of me.
要是我没说服他  他可能就把他们...
If I hadn't talked him down, he probably would've...
血淋淋的细节就不谈了  总之很惨
I'll spare you the gory details, but it was a deal and a half --
让人永生难忘啊
not something you forget.
你跟我说这些干嘛
And you're telling me this why?
别太苛责自己
Don't be too tough on yourself.
人们说  谨慎即大勇
Like they say, discretion is the better part of valor.
换我也会这样做
I would've done the same thing.
今天算我帮你  不收费
Hey, today, ‭it's on me -- no charge.
你搭下趟电梯
You take the next one.
照常收费
And bill me.
忘恩负义
Ingrate.
喂  吉米
Hey, Jimmy.
你跟霍华德说了吗
Did you tell Howard yet?
我现在还不能说
I can't really talk right now.
你没跟他说啊
You didn't tell him.
还没  等确定了我才能说
No, and I won't until it's rock-solid,
要等到录用通知书到手
like offer-letter-in-hand solid.
你什么时候能拿到录用通知书
When are you gonna get that offer letter?
下礼拜四吧
‭I'm guessing next Thursday,
跟合伙人面试过以后
After my interview with the partners.
-那只是走个流程吧  -差不多
- Yeah, but that's just a formality, right? ‭- Basically.
希望是
I hope.
到底给你开的什么条件
What's the offer you think?
我是说实质的
I mean, brass tacks.
比不上你在戴维斯梅因律所的
Well, it's not gonna be as much as your deal at Davis & Main,
但是两年后可以成为合伙人
but they'll make me partner in two years,
而在HHM需要五年或者永远不能
as opposed to somewhere between five years and never at HHM.
不错嘛
Not too shabby.
还帮我还法学院贷款
Yeah, and then there's my law-school loans.
还要还多少  几千块吗
What is that -- a couple grand by now?
只有几千就好了
I wish.
我还有其他开支
I had to finance the whole thing
当时还拿的是收发室工资
and was only making mailroom money.
还剩一万五没有还完
I've got ‭like $15,000 left.
斯韦卡特还真是想挖你啊
Schweikart wants you bad, huh?
但是  吉米
But, J -- but, Jimmy,
你找我有什么事
Did you have something you needed?
不不  就打电话问问
No, no. I was just checking in.
一会儿见  好吗
Uh, I'll see you later, okay?
如果你表现好的话
If you play your cards right.
拜拜
Bye.
奥马尔  你在哪
Omar, where are you?
奥马尔  帮我写封信行吗
Omar, would you be so kind as to take a letter for me?
"最亲爱的克利福德"  不  太过了
"Dearest Clifford..." No, that's too much.
"亲爱的克利福"
"Dear Cliff..."
你觉得应该叫克利福德还是克里福
Whaddaya think -- Clifford or Cliff?
我不知道  要看是什么信吧
I don't -- it depends on what the letter is.
没事  你看着写吧
That's fine. Treat yourself.
亲爱的  加什么都可以
Uh, "Dear..." Whoever you put in.
接下来  "我的心沉重得就像"
Continuing -- ‭uh, "My heart is heavy as --"
不行  听起来像是生病了
No, that sounds like a medical condition.
这么写吧
Let's go with, um,
"我怀着沉重的心情"  好吧
"It is with a heavy heart," Okay?
"我怀着沉重的心情向戴维斯梅因律所
"It is with a heavy heart that I tender my resignation
"正式提交辞呈"
"to Davis & Main."
用"提交"比"上交"好吧
"Tender" is better than "Submit," Yeah?
你说辞呈吗
Resignation?
是啊
Yes, sir.
"向戴维斯梅因律所提交...
So, "Tender," Blah, blah, blah, "To Davis & Main.
"在这里工作的日子
"These have been, uh,
"是我一生中最有职业成就感的一段时期"
"some of the most professionally satisfying days of my life..."
怎么了
What's wrong?
是不是说得有点过了
Do you think ‭I'm laying it on too thick?
不是...
No, um...
我只是没想到你在这里这么受气
I just didn't realize how unhappy you were here.
不是受气
Not unhappy, per se.
而是...不开心
More like... Not happy.
我完全没看出来
I had no idea.
不是你的错  伙计
‭It's not your fault, buddy.
你很能干
It's just -- you're top-notch.
我们写到哪了
Where were we?
可是你那么努力才争取到这一切
It's just y-you worked so hard to get here,
现在放弃的话你会失去很多
and it's so much to give up --
单说你的特别待遇
I-I mean, the perks alone.
是啊
Yeah.
公寓确实...不错
The apartment is, uh... Yeah.
还有车
And the car.
那辆车整体上是相当不错的
For the most part, car is pretty sweet.
还有签约奖金
And the bonus.
奖金已经到手了
The bonus is a done deal.
他们早就把支票给我了
It's -- ‭they already cut me the check.
奖金我可以留着
I get to keep the bonus.
除非你辞职
Not if you quit.
在一定时间内辞职  我记得你的是一年内
Before a certain term -- I think yours is a year --
你就要把钱还回来
You have to pay the money back.
是...
It's, um...
这个...
Yeah, uh, um...
对  就是这里...
Uh, uh, yeah, it's, uh...
应该是这儿
I think it's right, uh, there.
我看看
Yeah.
奥马尔  这个
Omar...That whole, ‭uh,
辞职信的事情
letter-of-resignation thing
我不是认真的  一个字也不作数
that -- I didn't mean that, not a word.
我...
I...
我只是  压力太大了
I-I'm so incredibly stressed out.
压力太大
I'm stressed out.
而且  坦白说
And frank-- to be honest,
适应戴维斯梅因的工作节奏
it has been more of an adjustment
比我预想中更困难
than I expected here at Davis & Main.
所以我有点  别把我刚才说的告诉别人
And so I just -- don't repeat what I said to anyone.
我就觉得有些不对劲
I figured ‭something had to be wrong --
肯定不对劲  因为你很喜欢在这里工作吧
I mean, really wrong because you like it here, right?
爱死了
I love it.
刚刚  就当是一瞬间失去理智吧
It -- call it ?A momentary lapse of reason.
我们
And but just --
我们忘了这回事吧
Let's just rewind the tape and, you know, forget this happened.
没问题  绝对不说出去
Mum's the word. No problem.
我感觉好多了
Yeah, I feel better already.
有时候必须把想说的大声发泄出来
I -- you know, sometimes, you have to say something out loud
才知道那听起来有多荒唐
to hear how crazy it sounds.
谢谢你  奥马尔
Thank you, Omar.
阿尔布开克  二十六英里
你好  吉米·麦吉尔
Hi, Jimmy Mcgill.
吉米  这位是联盟殡仪馆的艾尔·纽曼
Jimmy, this is Al Newman of Allied Funeral Homes.
很高兴见到你  艾尔
Great to meet you, Al.
-领带不错  -谢谢
- Nice tie. ‭- Thanks.
好了  我们开始吧
All right. Let's get started, shall we?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
道格  给办公室弄了台榨汁器
Hey, Doug! ‭Got a juicer for the office!
吉米  太吵了
Jimmy, it's very loud!
-布莱恩  进来  -我们的委托人在外面
- Brian, come on in! - We have clients out there!
-好的  两杯  马上  -吉米
- Sure, you can! Two coming right up! - Jimmy --
有时候塞太多会堵住
Sometimes, it gets a little jammed.
你得用力才行  像这样
You just got to force it. Yeah!
天哪
Oh, shit!
该死  溅得到处都是
Shi-- I'm -- I'm spreading it around.
-溅到你身上了吗  -没有
- Did I get you? ‭- Nah.
现在弄上了
I -- oh, ‭now I got you with this.
天哪  吉米
For Christ's sakes, Jimmy!
只能倒着来  明白吗
Backwards only -- solo backward-o, yeah?
因为这样才有吸力  杠杆原理啥的
Because, uh, you've got suction that way, leverage.
这是物理  物理
It's physics -- el physico!
克利福德先生希望地板干干净净
Oh, Don Clifford wants his floors clean --
清洁干净
limpio, limpiar.
明白吗[以上对话夹杂西语]
Uh. Comprende?
老兄  我是密歇根人
Dude, I'm from Michigan.
所以我刚才说的你一个字都听不懂
So you don't understand a word I've been saying.
那好吧
Well...
晚安
Good night.
来  你试一下  倒着吸
No, you try. Backwards.
不好意思
Excuse me.
请大家注意一下
Can I have everyone's attention, please?
都能听见吗  很好
Everyone can hear me? Good.
坦白说  我从没想到
Frankly, this is not a conversation
在自己的职业生涯中要进行这种讲话
I ever thought I would have in my professional career,
但我注意到
but it's been brought to my attention
洗手间出了状况
that we have an ongoing situation in the washroom.
有人上完不冲水
Someone is not flushing.
一次是意外  两次也是
Once is an accident -- maybe even twice.
三次就形成模式了
Three times -- no, that's a pattern.
而且还不是小便
And we're not talking about a number one.
是的  谢谢你  艾琳
Yes. Thank you, Erin.
我不是来给谁难堪的
Now, I'm not here to shame anyone --
我都不想知道是谁干的  但是...
Nor do I even want to know who did it, but --
克利福德  是我干的
Uh, Cliff, it was me.
吉米  我说了我不想知道
Jimmy, I just said I didn't want to know.
我们要节约水
Hey, we need the water.
我了解到圣达菲的水位
I read somewhere that the Santa Fe watershed
今年下降了五厘米
is down ‭two full inches this year.
每冲一次水
Every time you flush a toilet,
都会浪费一加仑水  一加仑呢
you waste a gallon of water -- a gallon!
还有比不冲水更好的节约方法吗
What could be greater than this?
那些都是低流马桶  吉米
They're low-flow toilets, Jimmy.
从现在开始  你要冲水
From now on, flush.
低流  不错啊
Low-flow -- that's good.
好主意
Good thinking.
什么声音
What is that?
吉米  里面怎么回事
Jimmy, ‭what's goin' on in there?
吉米
Jimmy!
你隔着门也能听见吗
Oh, you could hear this through the door?
我没注意到  抱歉
I didn't realize. I'm sorry.
你在干什么
What do you think you're doing?
我接受了你的建议
Uh, I took your advice.
释放压力
I'm blowing off steam.
Blowing off steam?
是啊  就像你弹吉他一样
Yeah, yeah, like you and your guitar, you know?
不得不说  你说得没错
Um, I got to say -- you're right.
这非常有助于缓解压力
I mean, ‭it really helps with stress.
声音不怎么好听  但我刚学
I know I don't sound very good, but I'm just learning.
我听说关键是要一直让这个气囊充气
I heard that the key is you have to keep this bag inflated.
够了
Enough!
赶紧给我放下来
Put that down. Now.
你来我办公室一趟
I want you in my office.
你赢了
You win.
我赢了什么
What do I win?
你被炒了
You're fired.
什么  克利福德  如果是因为那个风笛
What? Cliff, if this is about the bagpipes --
不是因为那个风笛
It's not about the bagpipes.
当然是因为风笛了
Well, of course it's the bagpipes.
是因为风笛  是因为不冲水
It's the bagpipes, ‭and it's the not flushing
还因为你这身...扎眼的所谓西裝
And this -- this optical migraine you call a business suit.
是因为...是因为你想保住你的奖金
It's about -- it's about you keeping your bonus.
都是因为这个
That's what this is about.
你最近一直在温习合同法吧
Been brushing up on ‭your contract law, haven't you?
你显然想离开这里
You want outta here, clearly,
但你不能辞职  否则奖金不保
But you can't just up and quit and expect to keep your bonus.
如果我因为你的不当行为解雇你
And if I fire you for cause --
在你拍广告时我就应该炒了你...
Like I should have done for the TV commercial --
奖金也没有
Again, no bonus.
但是
However,
如果无缘无故  就因为你是个混蛋而解雇你
if I fire you not for cause but for being an all-around jackass...
你就得逞了
Yeah.. ‭Hurray for you.
如果你认为我有什么渎职行为...
If you think there's been some malfeasance here --
省省吧
Oh, save it.
我可以和你争  但我不想浪费时间
I could fight you on this, but you're not worth my time.
你最好赶紧走人
I'd rather just have you gone.
你这么想我很抱歉
I'm sorry you feel that way.
我去...收拾东西
I'll just, uh... pack up.
首先...行行好
First... Do me the favor
不要把我当傻子
of not treating me like a fool for once.
告诉我  我到底对你哪里不好了
Tell me -- ‭how exactly did I mistreat you?
我到底做了什么让你这样对我
What did I do to deserve is kind of behavior?
我们给了你机会  鼓励你发展
We gave you opportunities, encouraged you to excel.
给你配了车  配了房
We got you a car, an apartment.
还有黄檀木办公桌
Hell, that cocobolo desk.
你在这儿看到过那样的桌子吗
Do you see a desk like that in here?
你根本没有认真考虑
You never gave this a chance.
为什么
Why?
我努力想要适应  真的
I tried to make it work -- really, I-I did.
我只是...不适合这里
I'm just... a square peg.
如果你早就知道  为什么还要接受这份工作
If you knew that, why did you take the job?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
那张桌子多少钱
How much was the desk?
七千
$7,000.
我会给你开张支票
I'll write you a check.
随便  虽然不知道有什么用
Fine, ‭for whatever good that does.
带上你的桌子离开这里
Take your desk and get out.
克利福德  不管怎样  我觉得你是一个好人
Hey, Cliff, for what it's worth, I think you're a good guy.
不管怎样  我觉得你是一个混蛋
For what it's worth, I think you're an asshole.
哈姆林先生
抱歉通知你  我将辞去
门开着
Uh, yeah, it's open.
-吉米  -我能和你谈谈吗
- Jimmy. ‭- Hey. Can I talk to you for a minute?
霍华德知道你来吗
Does Howard know you're here?
当然不知道  我溜进来的
God, no. I snuck in.
好吧  但是快点
Well, uh, yeah, but make it quick.
其实  我们能不能去会议室谈
Actually, can we, uh, talk in the conference room?
为什么
Why?
这样更正式
It's just more appropriate.
四点之前没人要开会  我看过了
Um, no one's gonna need it till 4:00 -- I checked.
行吗
Please?
最多十分钟
10 minutes, tops.
你先请
After you.
坐吧
‭Have a seat.
怎么...怎么回事
What -- what is going on?
说吧
Spill it.
好吧
Okay.
斯韦卡特考科利会帮你付清欠哈姆林麦吉尔的债务
Schweikart and Cokely will pay your debt to HHM
并在两年之后将你提拔为合伙人吧
and make you a partner in two years, correct?
显然是的
Apparently.
是这么约定的  怎么了
That's the deal, yes. Why?
要不要考虑一个更好的工作机会
Would you entertain a better offer?
谁给的  哈姆林麦吉尔联合律所吗
From whom -- HHM?
我
From me.
我明天就让你成为合伙人
I'll make you a partner tomorrow.
以此为证
Consider that proof of concept --
韦克斯勒麦吉尔联合律所
Wexler-Mcgill, partners at law.
你和我一起
You and me, together.
斯韦卡特可以帮你偿还债务  我也可以
If Schweikart can pay your debt, so can I.
再加上我的签约奖金
And with my signing bonus,
你就可以从头开始了
you'll have a clean slate.
前程无限好
The sky's the limit.
我俩合作很好的
Hey, we're good together.
这你知道的
You know that.
还犹豫什么
So, what's stopping us?
全身心投入  做自己的老板
Let's jump in with both feet, be our own bosses,
共建我们的未来
build our own future.
"做自己的老板"
"Be our own bosses."
哪里来的委托人呢
What about clients?
你刚刚签了梅萨维德银行  是吧
Mesa Verde just signed with you, didn't they?
想把他们挖走很难
It'll be a hard sell to take them with me.
那就再找一个梅萨维德
So, then there will be another Mesa Verde.
这全都靠你  金
That was all you, Kim.
你能签下这个  再签一个有何难
You did it once. You can do it again.
你说得轻松
You make it sound easy.
不  你面前的这个男人
No. You're talking to a guy
可是在美甲店里蜗居了多年
who lived ‭in the back of a nail salon.
肯定要付出很多心血和汗水
No, this is gonna be a whole lot of blood, sweat, and tears --
至少一开始肯定很艰难
at least, at the start.
但是最终我们会拥有完全属于我们的生意
But in the end, we'll have a practice that is 100% ours,
很值得
that's worth it.
也有可能失败  两手空空
Or we fail ‭and end up with nothing.
你说得对  这就是一场赌博
Well, you're right -- it's a gamble.
这是一场豪赌
It's a big one.
没错  但你是把赌注压在自己身上
Yeah, ‭but you're betting on yourself,
就我看来  你赢的几率很大
and from where I sit, the odds are in your favor.
你是一名出色的律师
You're an amazing lawyer.
这是你向世界展示的机会
This is your chance to show the world that.
那我为什么不去斯韦卡特呢
So, why not go to Schweikart?
他们也会让我成为合伙人
They'll make me partner,
而且他们律所可靠  声誉又好
and they are a solid, respectable firm.
这一点无可否认
You can't deny that.
你不该只满足于这样的横向调动
You deserve more than just a lateral move.
这就是斯韦卡特代表的
Bottom line -- that's what Schweikart represents.
他只是另一个霍华德·哈姆林罢了
He's just Howard Hamlin by a different name.
你一直在说我和斯韦卡特
You keep talking about me and Schweikart.
那你和戴维斯梅因怎么办
What about you and Davis & Main?
结束了  我今天辞职了
That's over. I quit today.
严格来讲  是我被炒了
Well, technically, I got fired.
怎么了
What happened?
互相看不顺眼  而且由来已久
It was mutual and a long time coming.
这份工作从一开始就不适合我
That job was never the right fit for me.
这份才是
This is.
如果我俩要成为律所合伙人
If we're gonna be law partners,
有一件事我需要确认
I need to know one thing.
你会是什么样的律师
What kind of lawyer are you gonna be?
我不是指你要专攻哪一法律  我指的是
I don't mean what kind of law are you gonna practice. I mean
你会照章办事吗
are you gonna play it straight,
还是继续
or are you gonna...
耍各种花招
be colorful?
我会照章办事  绝不出格
I'm gonna play it straight, right down the line.
我会万分谨慎
I'm gonna dot every "I," and I'm gonna cross every...
如果我不能做自己  那这又有什么意义
There's no point in me doing this if I can't be myself.
每一次我照着别人的方法来做事
Every time I try to do things someone else's way,
都会把事情搞砸
it blows up in my face.
在戴维斯梅因律所就是如此
That's what happened at Davis & Main.
看看结果如何
Look how that turned out.
我差点毁了你的事业  惹毛了所有人
I almost derailed your career, pissed everyone off.
我一直都努力活在别人的期望中
I've been trying to be the person someone else wants me to be for...
我也不知道有多久了
I don't know how long.
一开始是查克
I mean, first, it was Chuck,
然后是你  这并不是你的错
then it was you -- ‭and that's not your fault.
那是我自己的选择
That was my choice.
但是如果我们要这么做
But if we're gonna do this,
我要做我自己
I got to go into it as me.
所以  没错
So, yeah.
继续耍花招吧
Colorful, I guess.
你觉得怎么样
What do you say?
我只是
I just...
我不明白为什么我俩非要在一起工作呢
I don't see ‭why it's so important to you that we work together.
我们已经...
I mean, we're already...
你为什么还要拉我入伙呢
‭Why do you need me for this?
我不是需要你  我想要你
I don't need you -- I want you.
你已经拥有我了...
You've got me...
只不过不是合伙人
Just not as a law partner.
我得回去工作了
I have to get back to work.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
没事  我很好
No, I'm fine.
去吧
Go on.
那一会见
See you later? ‭
一会见
Yeah.
你也看到了  这房子可以拎包入住
It's move-in ready, as you can see.
在过去三年里已经重新装修过了
And they've renovated within the past three years --
地板和厨房都是新的
new floors, new kitchen.
空间也很大
And it's a good amount of space.
这房子不算太过吧
It's not too much house, you think?
一点也不过分
No, not at all.
看看那后院啊
And look at that backyard.
他们把小房子都留在这了
They're leaving the playhouse.
是不是很棒
Isn't that amazing? ‭
凯莉肯定爱死了
Kaylee will go crazy for that.
-她肯定进去了就不想出来  -是吧
- You'll never get her outta there. - I know, right?
最重要的是
And the most important part --
周围的学校很不错  邻居也很棒
the schools are good and the neighborhood is great.
我打了本警区的电话  问了犯罪率
I called the local precinct and asked about the crime stats --
这里是市里最低的地方之一
they're some of the lowest in the city.
而且  他的语气很好
Plus, I got a good vibe from him.
听起来很负责任
Like, they sounded really responsive.
这很不错
That sounds perfect.
是的
Yeah.
你喜欢吗
Do you like it?
你开心我就开心
If you're happy, I'm happy.
你喜欢吗
Do you like it?
是  我喜欢  但是我
Yeah, I do, but I'm --
-但是什么  -需要一大笔钱
- But what? - ‭It's a lot of money.
我知道我一直唠叨  但确实要很多钱
I know -- I'm like ‭a broken record, but it is.
这你不必担心
You don't worry about that.
无论多少钱都要买下来
We'll make it happen, whatever the cost.
-麦克  -我说真的
- Mike. - ‭Hey, I'm serious.
别多想了
Not another thought.
你想要就买吧
If you want it, it's yours.
房子怎么样
How we looking?
非常棒
Oh, it's perfect.
-成交  -非常好
- Let's do it. ‭- Fantastic.
你们还有时间吗
Do you have another hour?
我们可以去办公室
We could go down to the office,
申请贷款预批之类的
get the pre-approval in order, all that.
可以  我们在那儿见
Oh, sounds good. We'll meet you there.
行  一会儿见
Sure. See you in a few.
我终于能松口气了
Oh, I feel like I can finally breathe.
行  我很高兴
Good. I'm glad.
你想坐我的车吗
You wanna ride together?
不  我跟着你开
No, I'll follow you over.
车看起来还行嘛
Car looks good.
连剐蹭的痕迹都看不出来
Wouldn't even know ‭you so much as scratched it.
没错  修车工技术好
Yeah, um, my guy knows his stuff.
爸  谢谢你做的一切
Thank you, pop, for everything.
开车去吧
You go on now.
-我们在那儿见  -行
- I'll see you there. - ‭'kay.
抱歉  刚才红绿灯差点把你弄丢了
Sorry I almost lost you at that light.
没事
No problem.
小心鱼缸
Watch the fish tank.
左边
To the left.
我左边  我左边
My left, my left.
好了
There.
你觉得如何
What do you think?
行
Uh, yeah.
还挺...
It's, um...
还行
Yeah.
这东西要怎么处理
‭What should I... do with this?
丢到路边去
Dump it ‭on the side of the road --
我当初也是在路边捡的
That's where I got it in the first place.
-给  伙计  -不用
- Hey, buddy. - ‭Oh, no.
-你帮了我大忙  -真的没关系
- This is over and above. ‭‬- That's okay, really.
去喝一杯呢
How about a drink?
-我想喝一杯  -不用了
- I know I could use one. - ‭No.
来吧  我请客
Come on. I'm buying.
我真不用  开长途车
No, I'm good. Long drive.
喝些黄瓜水再上路
Cucumber water for the road?
没事的  谢谢
I'm -- I'm totally set. Thank you.
得回家照顾孩子
Gotta get home to my kids.
那你呢
How about you?
你现在准备怎么办
What are you gonna do now?
勇往直前
Onward and upward.
谢谢  奥马尔
Thanks, Omar.
一路平安
Drive safe.
你好
Hello!
这里是詹姆斯·M·麦吉尔先生的律所
You've reached the law offices of James M. McGill, esquire.
请留...
Kindly leave...
你好
Hi.
这里是吉米·麦吉尔的律所
You've reached the law offices of Jimmy McGill.
请留言
Please leave a message,
我会尽快回复
and I'll get back to you as soon as I can.
谢谢
Thanks.
简易判决吗  是的  我处理过六起
Summary judgments? Uh, yes. I've handled six.
其实最近一起非常复杂
Actually, one recently was quite complex.
一起诉讼案  离婚不顺造成的
It was a litigation -- the result of a nasty divorce.
我的委托人起诉她以前的公司
My client was suing her former company,
她和前夫在协议书中分了该公司的财产
which she and her ex had split in their settlement.
其中的问题让我研究了几周判例法
The issues involved had me chasing case law for weeks.
-谁审理的  -皮特曼法官
- Who heard it? ‭- Judge Pittman.
他很难缠啊
That guy -- he's a handful, huh?
他有时候是很难搞
Well, he can be a tough nut to crack,
但他做出了有利我的判决
but he did rule in my favor.
行了  别总说法律了
All right, ‭enough about law, law, law.
我们知道你很棒
We know you're good.
我们知道你很懂行
We know you know your stuff.
说说金·韦克斯勒
Tell us about Kim Wexler.
你从收发室干起
You started in the mailroom.
-是吧  -没错
- Is that right? - ‭I did.
这大概是十年前的事了
I was there almost, ‭uh, well, 10 years ago now.
一步一步往上爬  很不错
Pulled yourself up by your bootstraps -- I like that.
你上过新墨西哥大学法学院  你是新墨西哥人吗
I see you went to UNM law. Are you from New Mexico?
老家不在这
Not originally.
我是中西部人
I'm from the Midwest,
地图上都没有的小镇
Just a tiny, little town barely on the map --
堪萨斯和内布拉斯加交界处
You know, ‭that Kansas-Nebraska border.
你们肯定没听过
You've never heard of it.
那你怎么到这儿来了
So, what brought you here?
也许...
I guess...
有一天  我回顾人生  回顾曾经的我
Uh, one day, ‭I just looked around at my life, at who I was,
我意识到  如果继续走那条路的话
and realized if I kept going the way I was going...
哪条路
Which way was that?
最好的情况
Best case?
可能是嫁给镇上开加油站的那个人
Probably married to the guy that ran the town gas station.
也可能是在辛奇丁奇当个收银员
Maybe cashiering down at the Hinky Dinky.
-辛奇什么  -辛奇丁奇
- The Hinky what? - ‭Hinky Dinky.
我们那儿的超市
It was our supermarket.
我只是想要其他的东西
‭I just wanted something else.
你想要什么
What did you want?
更多
More.
感谢前来  和你聊天真高兴
Well, thanks for coming by. Always a pleasure.
总算见到本人了
Great to put a face to the name.
-谢谢  -我们要一起讨论一下
- Oh, thanks. - ‭We are gonna put our heads together and discuss,
但我可以保证
but I feel safe to say that you can expect
最晚明天就能给你消息
to hear from us by tomorrow at the latest.
那真是太棒了
That's... fantastic.
我很期待
I look forward to it.
你一走进来  我们就喜欢上你了
We liked you when you came in here.
现在更喜欢你了
We like you more now.
感谢你们抽出时间
Well, thank you so much for taking the time,
稍后再聊吧
and I will, uh, ‭speak to you soon.
认识你真高兴  琳恩
It was great to meet you, Lynne.
-我也是  -再见  派瑞
- You, too. - ‭Perry.
幸会  金
‭Pleasure, Kim.
-霍华德  -其实我是里奇
- Howard. - It's Rich, actually.
天啊  真是太抱歉了
Oh, my god. I'm so sorry.
不用  我很高兴你把我和霍华德弄混了
No, no, no, no. I'm happy to be confused with Howard.
他实在太帅了  别放在心上
He's a damn good-looking man. Don't worry about it.
来吧  我送你出去吧
Uh, come on. I'll walk you out.
你好  我想见吉米
Hi. I'm, uh, here to see Jimmy.
他正在开会
He's in a meeting.
-开会  -请坐
- A meeting? - ‭Have a seat.
听好
And, listen --
我不想再听到"许可证"这个词
I don't ever want to hear the word "Permit" again.
明白吗
Capisce?
你会遭报应的  哥们
It's your funeral, dude.
你在这儿干什么
What are you doing here?
正好来附近
Just in the neighborhood.
好
Great.
这次我想要台移动摄影车
Oh, and I want a dolly this time.
哪种  "西方"  "骗子"  "小家伙"
What kind? Western? Hustler? Pee-wee?
均为移动摄影车品牌
在女士面前注意措辞
Hey, watch your mouth around the lady.
我哪知道
How the hell should I know?
你才懂啊  便宜点就行
You're the nerd. Just make it cheap.
快去吧
Now, go on. Get outta here.
我看到你把旧车弄回来了
I see you got your old car back.
是啊
Yeah.
捐都捐不出去
The kidney people wouldn't take it.
抱歉
Sorry. ‭
你终于有张黄檀木办公桌了
Well, you finally got your cocobolo desk.
我终于有张黄檀木办公桌了
‭Finally got my cocobolo desk.
这是个好兆头
Feel like it's a good omen for what's next.
什么好事
And what's that?
就这个
This.
个体律所  又一次给自己打工
Solo practice, being my own man again.
和斯韦卡特的见面怎么样
So, how'd it go with Schweikart?
挺顺利的
Uh, went well.
明天就能拿到录用通知书了
Should be getting their offer tomorrow.
真不错
That's fantastic.
我真为你高兴
I'm really happy for you.
谢谢
Thanks.
我们应该庆祝
You know what? We should celebrate.
吃汉堡吧  我请客
Whataburger -- on me.
我不会接受那份工作
I'm not taking the job.
为什么
Why not?
你说得对  我应该做自己的老板了
You were right -- it's time for me to be my own boss.
个体律所
Solo practice.
怎么  你又觉得这么做不好了
‭What? You don't think it's a good idea now?
别告诉我你改变主意了
Don't tell me ‭you've changed your mind.
不  我很惊讶而已
No, ‭I'm -- I'm surprised, is all.
我一直都说
Hey, I s-- I said all along,
你太优秀  那帮乡巴佬不配
you're too good for those clowns.
这实在是...
I mean, this is, uh...
棒极了
Shit, yeah. Wow!
太棒了
It's great.
好
Good.
为此  我有个提议
To that end... I have a pitch for you.
不是韦克斯勒麦吉尔  而是韦克斯勒
Not Wexler-McGill, but Wexler...
以及麦吉尔
and McGill.
我们找间办公室  平摊物业费
We find an office, ‭share the housekeeping costs,
房租  电费  一切
the rent, electricity -- everything.
但我是律师金·韦克斯勒
But I am Kim Wexler, attorney at law,
你是律师吉米·麦吉尔
and you are Jimmy McGill, attorney at law,
我们都可以按自己意愿执业
both free to practice as we see fit.
同一屋檐下两间律所
Separate firms under one roof?
我们都要出城  为什么不拼车呢
We're both headed uptown, so why can't we share a taxi?
你按你的方式来  我按我的来
You do things your way, and I do them mine.
我们有自由
We'll have freedom,
但也不会孤军奋战
but we aren't each trying to go it alone.
不是合伙人  而是一起工作的个体律师
Not partners -- ‭solo practitioners, together.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
我不知道说什么好
I don't know what to say.
说同意吧
Say yes.